

#### **PROFIL**

Nationalities: Swiss & Italian

Born in: 1998 (26 yo)

Living in: Valais Switzerland

### COORDINATES

BenoitMuller82@gmail.com

Rue de la Bârre 32 3971 Chermignon-d'en-bas Suisse

+41 78 625 05 01

<u>abenoitmueller</u>

benoit-muller.github.io/ → academic projects

# **INTERESTS**

The scientific culture, the sharing of knowledge, the art of problem-solving.

"Everything should be made as **simple** as **possible**, but not simpler."

**Sports** of any kind. 15 years of **judo**: multiple times **Valais Champion**, bronze medalist at the **Swiss Kata Championships**. **Hiking** and **skiing** in the Valais Alps.

# Benoît MÜLLER

# **Applied Mathematics Engineer**

Seeking opportunities

to apply my mathematical and computational skills such as numerical analysis, across diverse industries.

#### **EDUCATION**

**EPFL** · Lausanne CH

- Master in **Applied Mathematics** (2021–2024) · Numerical analysis track.
- Bachelor in Mathematics (2018-2021).

LCP · Sion CH : Maturité Gymnasiale (2013-2018) · Strong mathematics.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Intern - The Countdown company -2024 (5 months)

R&D Group: Adapted an open-source topological optimization code in Code\_Aster, and presented specialized 3D printing path planning strategies.

#### Associative:

#### Associative member - EPFL - 2019 to 2023

- EscapEPFL: Communication manager.
- MA Travel: Organization and funding of the 2022 trip of the math section.
- Coaching MA: Coach of a first year students group, organization of events.

#### Sportive coach - Judo Team Sion - 2012 to 2018

Direction or assistance of the training for 5-18 years old fighters, management during competitions, referee intern.

# **SKILLS**

**Mathematics**: Strong general background, with a specialization in continuous problems.

# Numerical analysis:

- Continuous Nonlinear Optimization: constrained & unconstrained, on vector spaces & smooth manifolds, specialized methods for ML, optimal transport.
- **Computational Linear Algebra**: eigenvalues problems, linear systems, low-rank approximation techniques.
- Differential Equations: partial & ordinary, finite differences & elements, method of characteristics.

**Statistics & ML**: Probability, parameter inference, stochastic simulation, regression, dimension reduction, machine learning, deep learning.

**Programming**: Algorithmics, object-oriented & numerical programming. **Software & languages**: Python (NumPy, SciPy), MATLAB, GitHub, LaTeX, MS-Office. Basics of C++, PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, HyperMesh, OptiStruct, Salome\_Meca, Code\_Aster.

# **LANGUAGES**

• French : C2, mother thongue

Anglais : C1, professional working proficiency
Italian : B1, limited working proficiency

German : B1, limited working proficiency